Syed Ammar Ali

Contact: +971-566574190 Email: <<u>ammar065@gmail.com</u>>

Current Address: Flat#33, 6th Floor, Rolla Center Building, Rolla Sharjah, UAE.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

DOB : June 02,1990 Marital Status : Single Passport No : BG3349452 Nationality : Pakistani Languages : English,Urdu Visa Status: Job Visa

OBJECTIVE:

Seeking a challenging opportunity to demonstrate my abilities and skills aim for simultaneous achievment of corporate and personal goals in a rewarding organization offering a career growth and professional development.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

I am an Associate Chartered Certified Accountant(ACCA) and M.COM(Finance) with 4 year plus of diversified work experience in providing Auditing, Accounting services to clients while working with the EXL-Auditing(Sharjah), UHF Chartered Accountant firm, Ufone Telecommunication, Bank Alfalah and also 2 year plus experience as a commerce teacher assistant.

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES:

- Proficient knowledge and enthusiasm about VAT.
- Familiar with common ERP software(s) (Tally ERP 9,QuickBooks,Sage 50 and Peachtree) and other customized accounting software packages.
- Analytical and detailed problem solving ability, multitasking and flexibility with minimal supervision.
- Detail-oriented with skills of Financial Reporting, Taxation, Auditing and have extensive competence in accounting and finance systems.
- Proficient in Microsoft Excel Advanced, Word, PowerPoint and other office applications.

EDUCATION:

ACADEMIC:

 Chartered Certified Accountant (ACCA) –UK

Master of Commerce(M.COM)
Specialization in Finance

 Advance Diploma in Accounting & Business

Bachelor of Commerce(B.COM)

Intermediate of Commerce(I.COM)

Association of Chartered Certified Accountant (ACCA)-UK Islamia University Bahawalpur(IUB)

Association of Chartered Certified Accountant (ACCA)-UK Islamia University Bahawalpur(IUB) BISE Bahawalpur

CERTIFICATE:

- Intuit QuickBook Accounting Software
- Tally ERP Accounting Software
- MS Excel Advance

CAREER HISTORY:

Organization: EXL-Auditing (Dubai, United Arab Emirates)

Tenure: OCT 2018 - Till to date

Designation: Auditor Key Responsibilities:

- Performed testing procedures on cash, fixed assets, accounts receivable, intangible assets, prepaid expenses, accounts payable, deferred revenue, accrued liabilities, revenue, and expenses.
- Performed physical inventory observations in order to evaluate inventory levels and identified potential damaged or obsolete inventory.
- Performed detailed tests of transactions for significant account balances.
- Performed walk-throughs to understand financial reporting systems and to identify internal controls that reduce the risk of material misstatement of financial results.
- Ensured accuracy of supporting schedules provided by the client and appropriately agreed them to the account balances.
- Utilized detailed analytical procedures to analyze income statement and balance sheet accounts.
- Drafted audit reports write up observations and other sections of the audit report and presented to management.
- Completed audit wrap up.
- Communicated with clients to obtain required financial data to perform and complete fieldwork efficiently.
- Maintained effective time management while simultaneously worked on several projects/clients.
- Assisted clients in maintaining subsidiary and general ledgers by providing guidance in proper booking of A/P, A/R & payroll journal entries.
- Proactively identified, assessed, summarized and communicated internal control gaps to management.
- Maintained relationships with external customers.
- Delivered quality work through rigorous review of audit team work papers and results.
- Managed audit relationships at all levels from Staff to Partner to ensure clear and strong alignment.

Organization: UZAIR HAMMAD FAISAL & Co

Tenure: April 2016 – Jan 2018 Designation: Audit Trainee Key Responsibilities:

- Assist two years back date audit to ensure the accuracy and completeness.
- Evaluation of transaction accuracy and completeness.
- Reviewing and recommending improvement in accounting system, record keeping and internal control system.
- Reconciliation of all banking transactions.
- Assist in the preparation of internal audit report based on facts and figures.
- Verifying records with physical assets.
- Salary sheet review and analytical analysis based upon organizational policies.

- Monitoring verification of procurement process and ensuring proper documentation.
- Performed stock counts and duties as assigned.
- Adequate experience based upon sampling for audit purpose.

Ufone Telecommunication Franchise

Tenure: Mar 2014 – Feb 2016 Designation: Accountant Key Responsibilities:

- Maintain regular inventory counts and kept all stock up to date.
- Prepare and update the individual file for customers and follow up of receivables.
- Maintain and uptodate the petty cash account on regular basis.
- Prepare and update the file of supplier and timely payment to supplier.
- Maintain employees' payroll preparation and distribution of loans, advances and other adjustments.
- Perform monthly reconciliation of all banking transaction.

Bank Alfalah

Internship (DEC13 to FEB14)

- Assist customer with various financial transactions including deposits withdrawals and checks, developed communication skills with customers.
- Followed banking procedures to maintain work environment in a neat and orderly condition.
- Maintain friendly and professional customer interaction.

Millat College of Commerce

Teacher Assistant (Commerce)

NOV 2010 to Oct 2012

- Responsible for creating classroom materials that were distributed to all students throughout the course of the year.
- Conducted examinations and helped to set the question paper for class.
- Earned high marks for the quality and creativity of classroom teaching, lesson plans and instructional materials used in teaching.
- Established positive relationships with students, parents, fellow teachers and school administrators/staff.